Finance and Business, Division of; Records ua300
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Division of Finance and Business Records
1972-2000
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
State University of New York at Albany. Division of Finance and Business
ua300
4 cubic ft.
Contains the records of the Division of Finance and Business, which preceded the current Division of Finance and Administration. It was overseen by the Vice President of Finance and Business and was responsible for many administrative functions at the University: budget and accounting, personnel, facilities, security, and internal audit.
Access
Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.
Acquisition Information
All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Historical Note
The Division of Finance and Business was established circa 1977 to oversee a variety of campus departments that had previously operated separately. As of 1992, the departments directly overseen by the Vice President for Finance and Business were: Controller, Human Resources Management, Physical Facilities, and Financial Management and Budget. The current iteration of this Division is called the Division of Finance and Administration, a name that was adopted in 1998. The Division of Finance and Admininistration oversees a similar range of operations as its predecessor: financial departments and physical facilities.
Scope and Contents
Materials in this collection consists primarily of correspondence, policy and planning documentation, and reports. Topics covered include: Master Plan development; financial support for building construction and renovation; budget planning; development of the Center for Advanced Technology in Thin Film and Coatings; subject files on various aspects of campus facilities and services, including: recycling and waste management, parking, vehicle operations, and custodial services; Resource Allocation Methodoloy planning documentation; materials relating to the administration of the bus service; and documentation of New York State ethics regulations.
Arrangement of the Collection
This collection is organized in the original order that it was recieved in. Folders that were in poor condition have been replaced, maintaining the original folder titles.
Education, Higher--Administration; Budget; Budget process; Administrative records; Financial Records; UAlbany Finance & Business; State University of New York at Albany
- Five Year Prespective, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Message from Finance and Business, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Three Year Plans Finance and Business, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Finace and Business Division, Three Year Plan, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Finance and Business Division, Five Year Plan, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Annoucements from the Vice President, 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Office of Finance and Business, 1976-1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondces on Staff Expenses, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondces on Staff Expenses, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Quarterly Staff Meeting, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Division of newsletter, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondces for University Staff, 1976-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- F+B Newsletter, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Positioned Hring Freeze, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Three Year Plan Update, 1979 January 15 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Five Year Prespective, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Alllocations, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Annual Report of University Auxiliary Services, 1983 July 1-1984 June 30 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Financial Statements of Univeristy auxiliary Services, Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Audited Finanical Statements of the University Auxiliary Services, 1983 June 30 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- State Comptrollers Annual Five Year List: 1982 - 1987 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- RFP Alumni Development System, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Draft Audit Report, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Draft Audit Report from State Comptoller, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Staff Study Comparing SUNY Finances, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- State Comptrollers Annual Five Year List: 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Audited Financial Statements, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Car Receipts and petty cash reimbursements, Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Five Year Plan, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Five Year Plan, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Foreign Affairs Europe after Maastricht, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Programs and Priorities: Assessing a Decade, 1980-1990 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Five Year Plan Update, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Five Year Prespective ( Year Two), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Management By Objective Update, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Bus Service, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Bus Service - COTA, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Bus Service - Active, 1985-1992 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Bus Service, 1986-1991 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Busing Task Force, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Capitalize Albany, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- DayCare Center, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- DayCare Center, 1972-1991 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Diversity, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Drugs, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Dudley Observatory, 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Energy Conservation, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Enviornmental Decisions Committee, 1975-1980 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Ethics in Governement, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Ethics in Governement, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Management Effectivenss Task Force, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Flexibility, 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Foundation, SUNYA, 1976-1983 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Hazard Waste, 1986-1991 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Handicapped, 1977-1987 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Legal Procedures, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Ethics in Governement, 1996 May 2 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Performance, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- 10210 Giants, 1996-1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- 10260 Local Economy, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- 10280 National Weather Service, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- 10295 Plug Power, 1998 January 5 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- 103640 University and Technology - Academic Computing, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- 10366 Univerosty Computer and Technology - University Bus Systems, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- 10367 University and Technology - Integ Administartion System, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- 02050 Business Development, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- 02070 Colliegiate Licensing, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- 02080 Computer Store, 1994-1998 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- 02160 ResNet, 1996-1998 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- 02090 Computers for Frosh, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- 02110 SUNY Card, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- 02140 Video Communications, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- 02210 Parking Management, 1996-1998 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- 02310 Comprehensive Fee, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- 02350 ACC-NEC, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- 02380 LAN Management, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- 02390 Network Upgrade Project, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- 02450 Organizational Chart, 1990-1998 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- 02550 Master Plan, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- 02570 Clean Air/Water Act (Bond Program), 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- 02620 Facilities - Alumni Quad, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- 02650 Facilities - Dudley Observatory, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- 02670 Facilities - Sterling Property, 1996-1998 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- 02680 Physical Plant, 1996-1998 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- 02730 Vehicle Operations, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- 02740 Operations, 1997 February 4 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- 02760 Custodial, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- 02770 Custodial - Contract, 1996-1998 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- 02780 Recycling/ Waste Management, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- 02800 Shop Coordinator, 1995 June 30 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- 07015 Athletics Division 1, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- 07090 Central Council, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- 07110 GSEU, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- 08005 Academic Mission Review and Performance Reporting, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- 08040 Resource Allocation Method, RAM, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- 08040 Resource Allocation Method, RAM, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- 08100 Tuition, Differential, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- 05010 Advanced Thin Film Technology, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- CAT, 1998 October 30 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- 09020 (u) Albany Foundation, 1996-1998 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- 09030 Fuller Road Management, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- 40000 Master Plan, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- 40007 Master Plan - Space Steering Committee, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- 40010 Administartion Rehabilitation, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- 40030 Husted Hall Rehab, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- 40040 Life Sciences Building, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- 40060 Urban Corridor Study, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- 19220 Sate University History, 1992; 1998 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- 02196 Budget-Capital, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- 02197 Budget Reduction Plan, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Management by Objective, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- 08130 Graduate Student Union (GSEU), 1995 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- 19160 CAT (Center for Advanced Technology), 1993-1995 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- 20005 RESNET, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- 04110 TV (RFI for Dorms), 1994 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- 06190 Alumni Quad, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- 19110 423 State St. (Joint file), 1993-1995 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- SUNY 2000 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Five Year Perspective (Year Three), 1989 (Box 5, Folder 10)